{
  "quiz": [{
    "question": "moral code",
    "answer": "These rules are often expressed in statements about how people should behave, and the individual rules fit together to form the moral code by which a society lives."
  }, {
    "question": "morality",
    "answer": "The term morality refers to social conventions about right and wrong that are so widely shared that they become the basis for an established consensus."
  }, {
    "question": "Ethics",
    "answer": "Ethics is a set of beliefs about right and wrong behavior within a society"
  }, {
    "question": "software piracy",
    "answer": "For example, attitudes toward software piracy—a form of copyright infringement that involves making copies of software or enabling others to access software to which they are not entitled—range from strong opposition to acceptance of the practice as a standard approach to conducting business."
  }, {
    "question": "virtue",
    "answer": "A virtue is a habit that inclines people to do what is acceptable"
  }, {
    "question": "vice",
    "answer": "a vice is a habit of unacceptable behavior."
  }, {
    "question": "integrity",
    "answer": "A person who acts with integrity acts in accordance with a personal code of principles."
  }, {
    "question": "Morals",
    "answer": "Morals are one’s personal beliefs about right and wrong, while the term ethics describes standards or codes of behavior expected of an individual by a group (nation, organization, profession) to which an individual belongs."
  }, {
    "question": "Law",
    "answer": "Law is a system of rules that tells us what we can and cannot do. Laws are enforced by a set of institutions (the police, courts, law-making bodies). Legal acts are acts that conform to the law. Moral acts conform to what an individual believes to be the right thing to do. Laws can proclaim an act as legal, although many people may consider the act immoral—for example, abortion."
  }, {
    "question": "Foreign Corrupt Practices Act",
    "answer": "In 2011, IBM agreed to pay $10 million to settle civil charges arising from a lawsuit filed by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) alleging the firm had violated the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act for bribing government officials in China and South Korea to secure the sale of IBM products.(The act makes it illegal for corporations listed on U.S. stock exchanges to bribe foreign officials.) The bribes allegedly occurred over a decade and included hundreds of thousands of dollars of cash, electronics, and entertainment and travel expenses in exchange for millions of dollars in government contracts."
  }, {
    "question": "The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC)",
    "answer": "The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), which oversees large U.S. banks, accused Citibank in 2012 of failing to comply with rules intended to enforce the Bank Secrecy Act. This act is designed to deter and detect money laundering, terrorist financing, and other criminal acts. Citibank neither admitted nor denied the allegations, but the company did agree to provide the OCC with a plan outlining how it would bring its program into compliance."
  }, {
    "question": "Bathsheba syndrome",
    "answer": "The moral corruption of people in power, which is often facilitated by a tendency for people to look the other way when their leaders act inappropriately has been given the name Bathsheba syndrome—a reference to the biblical story of King David, who became corrupted by his power and success.13 According to the story, David became obsessed with Bathsheba, the wife of one of his generals, and eventually ordered her husband on a mission of certain death so that he could marry Bathsheba."
  }, {
    "question": "Cablegate",
    "answer": "Army Private First Class Bradley Manning is believed to be responsible for the release of thousands of classified U.S. embassy cables, which caused an incident that became known as Cablegate. The incident caused many to seriously question security at the Department of Defense and led to many changes in the handling of intelligence and other classified information at various U.S. intelligence agencies and departments."
  }, {
    "question": "CyberSource Corporation",
    "answer": "According to CyberSource Corporation (a subsidiary of Visa Inc. that offers e-commerce payment management services), online revenue lost to fraud increased 26 percent from 2010 to 2011 to the amount of $3.4 billion. This represents 1 percent of the $340 billion retail e-commerce sales for the United States and Canada."
  }, {
    "question": "Corporate social responsibility (CSR)",
    "answer": "Corporate social responsibility (CSR) is the concept that an organization should act ethically by taking responsibility for the impact of its actions on the environment, the community, and the welfare of its employees. Setting CSR goals encourages an organization to achieve higher moral and ethical standards. As highlighted in the opening vignette, Cisco is an example of an organization that has set and achieved a number of CSR goals for itself, and as a result is recognized as a highly ethical company."
  }, {
    "question": "Supply chain sustainability",
    "answer": "Supply chain sustainability is a component of CSR that focuses on developing and maintaining a supply chain that meets the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their needs. Supply chain sustainability takes into account such issues as fair labor practices, energy and resource conservation, human rights, and community responsibility. Many IT equipment manufacturers have made supply chain sustainability a priority, in part, because they must adhere to various European Union directives and regulations (including the Restriction of Hazardous Substances Directive, the Waste Electrical and Electronic Equipment Directive, and the Registration, Evaluation, Authorization, and Restriction of Chemicals (REACH) Regulation) to be permitted to sell their products in European Union countries. In many cases, meeting supply chain sustainability goals can also lead to lower costs. For example, since 2001, Intel has invested over $45 million in efforts to reduce its energy costs. As a result of those initiatives, the company has saved on average $23 million per year."
  }, {
    "question": "Organizations have at least five good reasons for pursuing CSR goals and for promoting a work environment in which employees are encouraged to act ethically when making business decisions",
    "answer": "• Gaining the goodwill of the community<br>• Creating an organization that operates consistently<br>• Fostering good business practices<br>• Protecting the organization and its employees from legal action<br>• Avoiding unfavorable publicity"
  }, {
    "question": "Goodwill",
    "answer": "Companies often have a formal statement of their values, principles, or beliefs. Companies needs to attract and maintain loyal customers."
  }, {
    "question": "Philanthropy",
    "answer": "(the desire to promote the welfare of others, expressed especially by the generous donation of money to good causes) is a great way to demonstrate it’s goodwill and looks great to stakeholders."
  }, {
    "question": "stakeholder",
    "answer": "A stakeholder is someone who stands to gain or lose, depending on how a situation is resolved.)"
  }, {
    "question": "Creating an Organization That Operates Consistently",
    "answer": "Organizations develop and abide by values to create an organizational culture and to define a consistent approach for dealing with the needs of their stakeholders—shareholders, employees, customers, suppliers, and the community. Being consistent also means that shareholders, customers, suppliers, and the community know what they can expect of the organization that it will behave in the future much as it has in the past."
  }, {
    "question": "Fostering Good Business Practices",
    "answer": "In many cases, good ethics can mean good business and improved profits. Companies that produce safe and effective products avoid costly recalls and lawsuits. (The recall of the weight loss drug Fen-Phen cost its maker, Wyeth-Ayerst Laboratories, almost $14 billion in awards to victims, many of whom developed serious health problems as a result of taking the drug.)"
  }, {
    "question": "Protecting the Organization and Its Employees from Legal Action",
    "answer": "In a 1909 ruling (United States v. New York Central & Hudson River Railroad Co.), the U.S. Supreme Court established that an employer can be held responsible for the acts of its employees even if the employees act in a manner contrary to corporate policy and their employer’s directions. The principle established is called respondeat superior, or “let the master answer.”"
  }, {
    "question": "Avoiding Unfavorable Publicity",
    "answer": "The public reputation of a company strongly influences the value of its stock, how consumers regard its products and services, the degree of oversight it receives from government agencies, and the amount of support and cooperation it receives from its business partners. Thus, many organizations are motivated to build a strong ethics program to avoid negative publicity. If an organization is perceived as operating ethically, customers, business partners, shareholders, consumer advocates, financial institutions, and regulatory bodies will usually regard it more favorably."
  }, {
    "question": "Improving Corporate Ethics",
    "answer": "Research by the Ethics Resource Center (ERC) found that 86 percent of the employees in companies with a well-implemented ethics and compliance program are likely to perceive a strong ethical culture within the company, while less than 25 percent of employees in companies with little to no program are likely to perceive a culture that promotes integrity in the workplace. A well-implemented ethics and compliance program and a strong ethical culture can, in turn, lead to less pressure on employees to misbehave and a decrease in observed misconduct. It also creates an environment in which employees are more comfortable reporting instances of misconduct, partly because there is less fear of potential retaliation by management against reporters (for example, reduced hours, transfer to less desirable jobs, and delays in promotions)."
  }, {
    "question": "The ERC has defined the following characteristics of a successful ethics program",
    "answer": "• Employees are willing to seek advice about ethics issues.<br>• Employees feel prepared to handle situations that could lead to misconduct.<br>• Employees are rewarded for ethical behavior.<br>• The organization does not reward success obtained through questionable means.<br>• Employees feel positively about their company."
  }, {
    "question": "Appointing a Corporate Ethics Officer",
    "answer": "A corporate ethics officer (also called a corporate compliance officer) provides an organization with vision and leadership in the area of business conduct. This individual “aligns the practices of a workplace with the stated ethics and beliefs of that workplace, holding people accountable to ethical standards.”"
  }, {
    "question": "Ethical Standards Set by Board of Directors",
    "answer": "The board of directors is responsible for the careful and responsible management of an organization. In a for-profit organization, the board’s primary objective is to oversee the organization’s business activities and management for the benefit of all stakeholders, including shareholders, employees, customers, suppliers, and the community. In a nonprofit organization, the board reports to a different set of stakeholders—in particular, the local community that the nonprofit serves. Essentially, the board of directors need to act as a role model for employees or else they’ll have some ethical troubles on their hands."
  }, {
    "question": "code of ethics",
    "answer": "A code of ethics is a statement that highlights an organization’s key ethical issues and identifies the overarching values and principles that are important to the organization and its decision making"
  }, {
    "question": "The Sarbanes–Oxley Act of 2002",
    "answer": "The Sarbanes–Oxley Act of 2002 was passed in response to public outrage over several major accounting scandals, including those at Enron, WorldCom, Tyco, Adelphia, Global Crossing, and Qwest—plus numerous restatements of financial reports by other companies, which clearly demonstrated a lack of oversight within corporate America. The goal of the bill was to renew investors’ trust in corporate executives and their firms’ financial reports. The act led to significant reforms in the content and preparation of disclosure documents by public companies. However, the Lehman Brothers accounting fiasco and resulting collapse as well as other similar examples raise questions about the effectiveness of Sarbanes–Oxley in preventing accounting scandals."
  }, {
    "question": "The Sarbanes–Oxley Act of 2002: Section 404",
    "answer": "Section 404 of the act states that annual reports must contain a statement signed by the CEO and CFO attesting that the information contained in all of the firm’s SEC filings is accurate. The company must also submit to an audit to prove that it has controls in place to ensure accurate information. The penalties for false attestation can include up to 20 years in prison and significant monetary fines for senior executives."
  }, {
    "question": "The Sarbanes–Oxley Act of 2002: Section 406",
    "answer": "Section 406 the act also requires public companies to disclose whether they have a code of ethics and to disclose any waiver of the code for certain members of senior management."
  }, {
    "question": "social audit",
    "answer": "An increasing number of organizations conduct regular social audits of their policies and practices. In a social audit (an official inspection of an individual's or organization's accounts, typically by an independent body.), an organization reviews how well it is meeting its ethical and social responsibility goals, and communicates its new goals for the upcoming year. This information is shared with employees, shareholders, investors, market analysts, customers, suppliers, government agencies, and the communities in which the organization Operates."
  }, {
    "question": "What was the ethical decision making tree?",
    "answer": "Develop Problem Statement<br>Identify alternatives<br>Evaluate and choose alternative<br>Implement decision<br>Evaluate results<br>Success? Then done! If not, do it again..."
  }, {
    "question": "Develop a Problem Statement",
    "answer": "A problem statement is a clear, concise description of the issue that needs to be addressed. A good problem statement answers the following questions: What do people observe that causes them to think there is a problem? Who is directly affected by the problem? Is anyone else affected? How often does the problem occur? What is the impact of the problem? How serious is the problem? Development of a problem statement is the most critical step in the decision-making process. Without a clear statement of the problem or the decision to be made, it is useless to proceed. Obviously, if the problem is stated incorrectly, the decision will not solve the problem."
  }, {
    "question": "Identify Alternatives",
    "answer": "During this stage of decision making, it is ideal to enlist the help of others, including stakeholders, to identify several alternative solutions to the problem."
  }, {
    "question": "Evaluate and Choose an Alternative",
    "answer": "Once a set of alternatives has been identified, the group must evaluate them based on numerous criteria, such as effectiveness at addressing the issue, the extent of risk associated with each alternative, cost, and time to implement. An alternative that sounds attractive but that is not feasible will not help solve the problem."
  }, {
    "question": "Methods Of Making Ethical Decisions",
    "answer": "1. Virtue ethics approach:<br>--->The ethical choice best reflects moral virtues in yourself and your community.<br>2. Utilitarian approach:<br>--->The ethical choice produces the greatest excess of benefits over harm.<br>3. Fairness approach:<br>--->The ethical choice treats everyone the same and shows no favoritism or discrimination.<br>4. Common Good Approach<br>--->The ethical choice advances the common good."
  }, {
    "question": "virtue ethics approach",
    "answer": "The virtue ethics approach to decision making focuses on how you should behave and think about relationships if you are concerned with your daily life in a community. It does not define a formula for ethical decision making, but suggests that when faced with a complex ethical dilemma, people do either what they are most comfortable doing or what they think a person they admire would do. The assumption is that people are guided by their virtues to reach the “right” decision. A proponent of virtue ethics believes that a disposition to do the right thing is more effective than following a set of principles and rules, and that people should perform moral acts out of habit, not Introspection."
  }, {
    "question": "utilitarian approach",
    "answer": "The utilitarian approach to ethical decision making states that you should choose the action or policy that has the best overall consequences for all people who are directly or indirectly affected. The goal is to find the single greatest good by balancing the interests of all affected parties."
  }, {
    "question": "fairness approach",
    "answer": "The fairness approach focuses on how fairly actions and policies distribute benefits and burdens among people affected by the decision. The guiding principle of this approach is to treat all people the same. However, decisions made with this approach can be influenced by personal bias, without the decision makers even being aware of their bias. If the intended goal of an action or a policy is to provide benefits to a target group, other affectedgroups may consider the decision unfair."
  }, {
    "question": "common good approach",
    "answer": "The common good approach to decision making is based on a vision of society as a community whose members work together to achieve a common set of values and goals. Decisions and policies that use this approach attempt to implement social systems, institutions, and environments that everyone depends on and that benefit all people. Examples include an effective education system, a safe and efficient transportation system, and accessible and affordable health care."
  }, {
    "question": "Implement the Decision",
    "answer": "Once an alternative is selected, it should be implemented in an efficient, effective, and timely manner. This is often much easier said than done, because people tend to resist change. In fact, the bigger the change, the greater the resistance to it. Communication is the key to helping people accept a change. It is imperative that someone whom the stakeholders trust and respect answer the following questions:<br>• Why are we doing this?<br>• What is wrong with the current way we do things?<br>• What are the benefits of the new way for you?<br><br>A transition plan must be defined to explain to people how they will move from the old way of doing things to the new way. It is essential that the transition be seen as relatively easy and pain free."
  }, {
    "question": "Evaluate the Results",
    "answer": "After the solution to the problem has been implemented, monitor the results to see if the desired effect was achieved, and observe its impact on the organization and the various stakeholders. Were the success criteria fully met? Were there any unintended consequences? This evaluation may indicate that further refinements are needed. If so, return to the develop a problem statement step, refine the problem statement as necessary, and work through the process again."
  }]
}
